最初  一切浑然一体
In the beginning, there was only one.
只有一片漆黑的无限空间
A single black infinitude.
后来无限空间找到了释放口
Then the infinitude found release,
最终  黑暗被冲破
And finally, the darkness broke,
凭借多元宇宙...
filling it with life...
使其中充满生命
With the multi-verse.
每一个存在都有多种可能性
Every existence multiplied by possibility,
并在空间和时间之前无限展开
and spread out before space and time in infinite measure.
文明起起落落
Civilizations rose and fell.
并在现实的广阔空间中再次兴起
And rose again across reality's grasping expanse.
生命  一份珍贵的礼物
Life. A precious gift
坚忍着面对每个障碍
persevering in the face of every obstacle,
直到英雄时代最终诞生
until, finally, the age of heroes was born.
混沌  生命永恒的敌人
Chaos. The constant enemy of life
被来自多元宇宙的勇士们所牵制
kept at bay by champions from across the multi-verse...
勇士们联手代表所有创造而战
...joining forces to fight on behalf of all creation.
他们及时找到了彼此
They found each other just in time,
因为此时  整个多元宇宙
because now, the entire multi-verse
地球八十九  哥谭市
即将受到攻击
is about to come under attack.
蝙蝠侠逮捕小丑
有一股邪恶的力量正在行动
There is a malevolent force at work,
它的目标只有一个
one driven by a singular goal.
但愿你在看  大个子
I hope you're watching, big guy.
地球九  旧金山
那就是毁灭一切
The destruction of all there is.
地球X
我拟定了计划
I have planned,
也有人说这是我的阴谋
there are those who say I have schemed,
地球六十六  哥谭市
但准备时间已过
but the time for preparation has passed.
危机如今降临到我们所有人头上
The Crisis is now upon us all.
死亡的血色苍穹
Holy crimson skies of death!
超女  第五季  第九集
无限地球危机  第一篇
地球三十八  中城
世界末日就要来了
The end of the world is licking at our heels!
准备迎接你们的厄运  世界末日即将来临
不久  你们将化为尘土
Soon, thou shall be not but dust,
在太空深处扭转翻滚
twisting and writhing in the dead of space!
就连超女也救不了你们
Not even Supergirl will save you from...
看来超女还是能救你们的
Guess Supergirl was able to save you.
赶紧走  快跑
Now, go! Run!
尖刺  还记得我吗
Hey, Spike! Remember me?
伊拉娜很担心你
Ilana's worried about you.
她知道你害怕某样东西
She knows you're afraid of something,
但她只想让你回家
but she just wants you to come home.
过来
Come here.
你被什么吓成这样  伙计
What's got you so spooked, buddy?
准备迎接你们的厄运  世界末日即将来临
纳欣诺市的每一只宠物都精神崩溃了
Every pet in National City is having a nervous breakdown.
这次感觉比利维坦还严重
This feels bigger than Leviathan.
美国地质调查局没有发出预警
The USGS didn't register an early warning,
所以这完全出乎所有人的意料
so it took everyone completely by surprise.
确实是所有人
She does mean everyone
因为这次地震是全球性的
because this earthquake is quite, literally, worldwide.
但是地震活动并非来自地球内部
But the seismic activity wasn't coming from within the planet,
而是来自外部
it's coming from without.
-这很...  -超常
- That's-- - Extra-normal.
我本想说"不可能"  但说"超常"也行
I was gonna say "impossible," but okay.
是的  这个描述很到位  正如...
Yes, yes, a fair descriptor. As would be, uh...
"不可行  不可思议  荒谬  古怪"
"Unfeasible, unthinkable, absurd, outlandish."
但是不管你怎么描述它
But however you choose to describe this
有一件事是绝对肯定的
one thing is absolutely certain.
-我们正...  -面临一场严重的危机
- We have-- - A major crisis on our hands.
监视者释放了马拉  我都不知道他是这个宇宙的人
The Monitor freed Mal? I didn't know he was of this universe.
我以为监视者是闪电侠和绿箭侠要操心的问题
Yes, I thought the Monitor was a Flash and Green Arrow's problem.
他存在于每个宇宙  是所有人要操心的问题
He's of every universe and everyone's problem.
去年  他利用迪根医生和《命运之书》
Last year, he tested Kara and Earth-1's heroes
考验了卡拉和地球一的英雄们
with Dr. Deegan and the Book of Destiny.
今年  他要考验我  看我是否为此做好了准备
This year, he's testing me to make sure I'm ready for this.
这到底是什么
And what exactly is this?
-另一种现实波吗  -不是
- Another reality wave? - Not exactly.
无论这是什么
Whatever is it,
它正以不可能的速度在太空中穿梭
it is hurtling through space at an impossible speed.
我估计它将于5.3小时之后
I calculate it will reach the edge of the universe
到达宇宙的边缘
in exactly 5.3 hours,
到时  它将原路返回
at which point, it will boomerang back.
一旦它再次与我们的太阳系相交
Once it intersects again with our solar system,
结果将是灾难性的
the results will be, in a word, cataclysmic.
它到底何时能到我们这里
Exactly when will it reach us?
需要精确计算的变量太多了
There are too many variables to calculate precisely,
但有一件事我敢肯定
but I will say this.
如果在明晚之前不阻止这道波
If this wave isn't stopped by tomorrow night...
我们将不复存在
there will be no more us...
未来和一切都将不复存在
no more future... no more anything.
它的轨迹上存在有人居住的行星吗
Are there any inhabited planets in its trajectory?
只有一个
Just one.
阿尔戈市
Argo City.
-天呐  超人和露易丝在上面  -还有我妈
- Oh, my God. Superman's there with Lois and... - My mom.
我们能提醒他们吗
Can we warn them?
阿尔戈的哈伦·艾尔让通讯变得很困难  但我会尽力
Argo Harun-El sure makes communication difficult, but I will try.
-他们有多少时间逃生  布莱尼  -来不及了
- How much time do they have, Brainy? - Not enough.
阿尔戈市
超人  地球的勇士
Superman, champion of Earth,
曾直面世界末日
who faced off with Doomsday,
逮捕佐德将军
apprehended General Zod,
与莱克斯·卢瑟的
and went toe-to-toe
几十个死亡陷阱近距离对峙
with dozens of Lex Luthor's death traps,
而他终于遇到了对手
has finally met his match.
一块脏尿布
A dirty diaper.
你怎么看  这能上头条新闻吗
What do you think? Front page news?
我觉得这对露易丝·莱恩来说有点浅薄
I mean, I think it's a little lowbrow for Lois Lane.
浅薄
Lowbrow?
要是地球上的公民
If only the citizens of Earth
能看到卡·艾尔跟粑粑作战就好了
could see Kal-El struggling with spit up.
需要我提醒你吗  莱恩小姐
Need I remind you, Miss Lane,
我在这里没有超能力
uh, I have no powers here.
别把这归咎于红太阳  亲爱的
Oh, don't you be blaming this on the red sun, honey.
儿子
Hey, buddy.
-老爸做到了  -算是吧
- Yay, Daddy did it. - Yeah, kinda.
乔纳森的眼睛很像你
Jonathan really has your eyes, huh?
这我接受
I'll take it...
只要他的其他部位都像你就行
so long he has your everything else.
我以前设想我们在一起的场景时
You know, when I used to picture us together,
我们总是生活在地球上
we were always living on Earth,
而且我们有两个孩子
and we had two kids.
我也不想扫你的兴  堪萨斯州小伙
Well, I hate to break it to you, Kansas,
但预言可不是你的超能力之一
but prognostication is not one of your superpowers.
卡尔  露易丝
Kal, Lois...
卡拉  你竟然穿着裤子
Kara? In pants?
她是怎么突破
How did she manage to break through
阿尔戈的屏障干扰的
Argo's shield interference?
显然没有彻底突破
Not well, apparently.
卡尔  露易丝  阿尔戈有危险
Kal, Lois... Argo is in danger.
你们需要马上撤离
You need to get out now!
阿露拉
Alura!
卡尔  露易丝  谢天谢地
Kal, Lois, thank God.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
一股巨大的能量正在太空中移动
A massive energy is moving through space.
它所到之处  无人幸免
It's killing everything in its path.
-我们还有多少时间  -几分钟而已
- How long do we have? - Minutes!
快  跟我来
Quickly! With me!
我们必须设定一条前往地球的航线
We must set a course for Earth.
希望他们有足够的时间
Hopefully, they'll have enough time
在这道波到达前阻止它
to stop this wave before it hits.
其他太空舱呢
Where are the rest?
没有其他的了  只有这一艘
There are no others. Only this one.
我们会永远跟你在一起  乔纳森
We'll always be with you, Jonathan.
我们决不会离开你
We will never leave you.
即使面对死亡
Even in the face of our deaths.
我们爱你
We love you.
他们不见了
They're gone.
阿尔戈  无信号
下面轮到我们了
And we're next.
地球一  炼狱
很久以来  我一直讨厌这个地方
For a very long time, I have hated this place.
一想到它从我身边夺走了那多人
I think about all the people that it took from me.
我就...  我就气愤不已
It would just... It would just make me so angry.
但你现在不生气了
But you're not now.
我还是有点生气
I'm still a little bit angry.
这座岛教会了我如何生存
This island taught me to survive.
它把我变成了另一个人
It turned me into someone else.
比以前更好的人
Somebody better than the person I was before.
所以  不管我的感觉如何
So, despite my feelings...
如果我不去炼狱的话
there are no stories about the Green Arrow to tell
就不会有绿箭侠的故事
if I don't make my way to Lian Yu.
这一刻  我也不可能站在这里
And I'm also not standing, at this moment...
看着我的女儿
looking at my daughter.
谢谢你让我参与你的故事
Thank you for letting me be a part of your story.
即使只是一小会儿
Even if it was only for a little while.
是啊  我觉得你会创造自己的故事
Yeah, something tells me you're gonna create your own stories.
莱拉
Lyla.
危机已经开始
The Crisis has begun.
地球一  中城
西斯科  你有什么消息
Cisco, what have you got?
这是孤立事件吗  还是无所不在
Is this an isolated event? Is it everywhere?
西斯科
Cisco?
爱瑞丝
Iris!
-莱拉  -我现在是先驱者
- Lyla? - I'm Harbinger now.
我在与监视者合作
I'm working with the Monitor.
他派你来接我
He sent you to get me?
-因为危机来了  -是的
- Because the Crisis is here? - That is correct.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
地球一  哥谭市
将目光转向本地新闻
Turning our attention to local news,
"仙境帮"的一系列劫案仍在继续
a series of robberies by the Wonderland Gang continues
似乎不打算停息
with seemingly no end in sight...
爱丽丝在哪
Where is Alice?
我问你们  "爱丽丝在哪"
I said, "Where is Alice?"
好了  我告诉你
Okay... okay, I'll tell you.
-有一家旧糖厂  -在哪里
- There's an old sugar factory. - Where is it?
蝙蝠女侠  多元宇宙处于危险之中  我们需要你
Batwoman, the multi-verse is in great danger. You are needed.
我等会再处理你那档子破事
I'll deal with, whatever your crazy is, in a minute.
没时间了
There is no more time.
地球一  星城
好了  各位  下面是今晚的决胜一题了
Okay, folks, time for our tie-breaker question of the night.
请听题
Here we go.
珍妮丝·贾普林录制的最后一首歌叫什么名字
What is the name of the last song Janis Joplin ever recorded?
准备好喝免费饮料了吗
Ready for some free drinks?
最后一道附加题的答案是...
And the answer to our final bonus question is...
《小机器男人》
"Little Robot Man."
陌生游客是今晚的赢家
The strange visitors are the winners tonight.
祝你们下次好运  传奇
Better luck next time, legends.
你们搞错了
Uh, no, that's wrong.
《梅赛德斯·奔驰》才是珍妮丝·贾普林的最后一首歌
But "Mercedes Benz" was Janis Joplin's last song.
我去告诉那个问答主持人
I'm gonna tell that trivia host.
莎拉
Sara.
你还记得去年在伍德斯托克音乐节
So, you remember last year at Woodstock
我应该偷
when I was supposed to steal a lock of
珍妮丝·贾普林的一缕头发吗
Janis Joplin's hair without her noticing?
-结果呢  -她发现了我
- Yeah? - Uh, she noticed.
-然后她管我叫  -"小机器男人"
- Then she called me-- - "Little Robot Man."
恭喜  你改变了历史
Well, congratulations, you change history
还害我们输了问答之夜
and lost us trivia night.
我们结束了
And we're done here.
莱拉  你怎么穿成这样
Lyla? What's with the suit?
恐慌正在蔓延
Panic is rising out there.
地球三十八  超查部
我希望所有待命的特工都出去调查
I want every available agent in the field
直到我们搞清楚这件事
until we get a handle on whatever this thing is.
趴在地板上  快点
Face down on the floor. Now!
这是你干的吗  你摧毁了阿尔戈
Did you do this? Did you destroy Argo?
天呐  你们没事
Oh, my God, you're okay.
多亏了她
Thanks to her.
她在最后一刻出现  把我们带到了这里
She appeared at the last second and brought us here.
我们让乔纳森坐着逃生舱离开了
We sent Jonathan off in an escape pod.
我母亲呢
And my mother?
我很遗憾  卡拉
I'm so sorry, Kara.
卡拉
Kara?
我们这是在哪  刚才发生了什么
Where are we? And what just happened?
你们在地球三十八上
You're on Earth-38.
有...
There was-- -
那只兔子就快开口了
That rabbit was about to talk.
这家伙会跟兔子说话
This one speaks to rabbits.
没关系  我们是同一战线的
It's okay. 'Cause we're all on the same side.
是吗  我根本不认识他们
Are we? 'Cause I don't know them.
但你认识我
But you know me.
如果你和其他英雄一起被带到了这里
And if you were brought here with all these other heroes,
可能是因为我们需要你
it's probably because we need you.
我信任在场的每一位
I trust everyone in this room with my life.
包括你
Including you.
你们叫我凯特就行
Well, I guess you should all just call me Kate.
是啊  这样就说得通了
Yeah, yeah, that makes a lot of sense.
我是米娅  奥利弗的女儿
Uh, I'm Mia. I'm Oliver's daughter.
我从来不知道他还有个女儿
I never knew he had a daughter.
经常有人这么说
He gets that a lot.
好了  你  开始说吧
Okay, you. Start talking.
有一道反物质波正席卷整个宇宙
There's a wave of anti-matter sweeping across this universe,
摧毁着它途经的一切
destroying everything in its path.
我见证了反物质波的威力
I've seen the anti-matter wave in action.
它彻底摧毁了地球二的存在
It wiped all of Earth-2 right out of existence.
我把你们都带到了地球三十八
I brought you all to Earth-38
因为监视者希望你们坚守在这里
because this is where the Monitor wants you to make your stand.
这个宇宙是临界点
This universe is the tipping point.
如果我们不能在这里阻止反物质波
If we don't stop the anti-matter wave here,
它将前往下一个宇宙
it will continue to the next universe,
并不断地向前推进
and the next, and the next.
直到它毁灭每一个地球
Until it has obliterated, not only every Earth,
以及所有现实中的
but every thing...
一切
across all reality.
所以我们需要一支更庞大的团队
Right. So, we are going to need a bigger team.
巴里呢  传奇又在哪里
Where's Barry? Where are the legends?
在做侦察
Doing reconnaissance.
我现在就去看看他们
I'm headed to check on them now.
我还是不喜欢她
I still don't like her.
布莱尼的算法将帮我们预测
Well, Brainy's algorithm will help forecast
反物质波具体还有多长时间到达这里
exactly how much time we have until the anti-matter wave hits.
感谢大家的到来
Thank you all for being here.
我知道我们能一起战胜它
I know we can beat this together.
关于乔纳森
About Jonathan...
我们给他的逃生舱设定了前往地球的航线
we set a course for Earth in his pod,
但我们不知道它具体在哪里着陆
but we don't know where it landed.
甚至不知道它有没有着陆
Or even if it landed.
布莱尼  你能追踪他的轨迹吗
Brainy, can you track his trajectory?
当然
Absolutely.
我们一眨眼的功夫就能找到
We'll find that bouncing bundle of Kryptonian joy
那个氪星开心果
faster than a flying Flackurian--
我们遇到新问题了
This is a new problem.
我能应付
I can handle it.
等等  那座塔构不成威胁
Wait, the tower isn't a threat.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
这显然是一座量子塔
It's a quantum tower, apparently.
它是唯一能拯救世界人民的东西
And it's the only thing that can save the people of this world.
在时间之初
At the dawn of time,
监视者在关键的地球上放置了量子塔
the Monitor placed quantum towers on key Earths
作为最后一道防线
as a last line of defense.
红色天空正在消散  这意味着它正在起作用
The red skies are dissipating, which means it's working.
从这个设计上看  这座塔能够
From this design, it looks like the tower is capable
产生量子流场
of generating a quantum flux field,
它在理论上可以...
which can, theoretically--
逆转反物质波的外成状态
Reverse the exogenic state of the anti-matter wave,
从而消耗反物质能量
thereby dissipating the anti-matter energy.
是的  终于找到我的同类人了
Yes. Finally, someone who speaks my language.
我喜欢你的战服
Love your suit.
如果你愿意  我可以帮你升级
If you want, I can probably give it an upgrade.
你还想要这只手吗
Depends on how attached you are to your hand.
非常想
Pretty attached.
所以这座塔能阻止这个地球被摧毁吗
So the tower can stop this Earth from being destroyed?
前提是你们能保护好它
If you can protect it.
-谁想破坏它  -反监视者
- Protect it from what? - The Anti-Monitor.
他指挥的武装力量比任何军队都庞大
He commands forces greater than any army.
当量子塔挡住波频时
When the tower stops the wave,
他们会来阻挠
they will come to thwart
任何拯救星球以及在此生存之人的努力
any effort to save this planet and its people.
坏了
Sprock!
乔纳森的逃生舱从我们的雷达上消失了
Jonathan's pod has disappeared from our radar.
似乎被吸进了一个虫洞
It appears to have been sucked into a wormhole.
-坐标是什么  -星城  地球十六
- What are the co-ordinates? - Star City. Earth-16.
有意思
Interesting.
逃生舱信号中断
星城  地球十六
2046年
虫洞肯定是临时出现的  因为...
It must've been a temporal wormhole because...
逃生舱现在在2046年
well, the pod is in the year 2046.
我们已经去过那里
We've been there before.
显然  我们不只是穿越到未来
Apparently, we didn't just travel to the future.
我们穿越到未来的平行地球
Yeah, we traveled to a parallel Earth in the future.
好极了
That's great.
-我要去找他  -克拉克  你不能去
- I'm going after him. - Clark, you can't.
我不习惯听到"不能"二字  而且我儿子需要我
Those are two words I'm not used to hearing and my son needs me.
我也身为人父  我明白
I'm a parent and I get it.
整个宇宙需要你
The entire universe needs you.
量子塔遇袭的时候
When that tower gets attacked,
你必须要保护它
you have to be here to protect it.
我去吧
I'll go.
露易丝
Lois...
我来支援你
I'll back you up.
-我了解地形  -我也会去支援
- I know the terrain. - As will I.
碰巧我很擅长跟小孩子相处
I happen to be excellent with children.
别担心  我会找到他的
Don't worry, I'll get him.
我爱你
I love you.
你知道吗  奥利弗
You know, Oliver...
我见过花花公子奥利弗
I've seen playboy Oliver,
义警奥利弗
vigilante Oliver,
但我从来没过会见到当爸爸的奥利弗
but I never thought I would see parent Oliver.
-很怪对吧  -很怪
- It's weird, right? - So weird.
但是你当爸的模样不错
But... it looks good on you.
荣恩  丹弗斯局长不是和你一起吗
J'onn, I-I-I thought Director Danvers was with you.
之前是
She was.
但是她去给总统打电话协调疏散
But she went to call the president to co-ordinate the evacuation,
以防量子塔失败
in case the quantum tower fails.
她很聪明  这正是我想建议的
She is smart, that is exactly what I was about to suggest,
但是她有没有想过这样一场大逃亡
but has she contemplated the number of ships
需要多少艘飞船呢
one would require for such an exodus?
布莱尼  这个星球上的所有外星人难民
Brainy, every alien refugee on this planet
都是坐飞船来到这里的
came here on a ship.
我打算向他们求助
I intend to ask them for their help.
你真的觉得他们会帮忙吗
Do you really think they will?
在去年政府那样对待他们之后
After how the government treated them last year.
我有信心  每个人都会做正义之事
I have faith that... everybody will do the right thing.
人类和外星人都一样
Humans and aliens alike.
在任何情况下
Well, in any event...
这个都应该有用
this should help.
坏了
Oh, Sprock.
我刚想到如何找到乔纳森在星城的位置
I just managed to zero in on Jonathan's location in Star City.
总统同意了  他在和其他世界领袖通话
The president is in. He's speaking with other world leaders.
我们会在纳欣诺市协调配合
We'll co-ordinate the effort from National City.
但是荣恩
But J'onn...
就算我们能为所有人准备充足的飞船
even if we did manage to get enough ships for everyone,
我们也不能就这样飞离地球
we can't just fly off Earth.
太空本身正在遭到毁灭
I mean, space itself is being erased.
地球一是反物质轨道的最后一关
Earth-1 is the last stop on the anti-matter trajectory.
我们可以尽量让大家去那里
We can try and get everybody there.
一个小小的外推器根本不可能做到
Well, one little extrapolator is not gonna do the job.
物质传送门呢
The transmatter portal?
谁能造出一个足够大的呢
Who could build one big enough?
就连布莱尼都不行
I mean, not even Brainy has.
莉娜
Lena.
她替达克萨姆人造过一个巨大的物质传送门
She built an enormous one for the Daxamites.
我相信她可以造出一个比那大两倍的
I'm sure she could build one twice as big.
不行  太冒险了
No, that's too big of a risk.
自从她偷了大清洗  还有那一切事情后
I mean, after Myriad, after everything...
我们不能相信她
she can't be trusted.
我们还有别的选择吗
What other choice do we have?
你母亲的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your mom.
我没能救她
I couldn't save her.
你在阿尔戈没有超能力  你也无能为力
You had no powers on Argo. There was nothing you could do.
我觉得自己像个傻子
I feel like a fool.
我以为我能放弃这件披风
I thought I could give up the cape and just...
拥有我想要的一切
have everything I ever wanted.
但是现在  阿尔戈没了
And now, Argo is gone,
这个地球危在旦夕
this Earth is in danger,
露易丝和乔纳森还身处在宇宙中
Lois and Jonathan are out in the universe,
我却保护不了他们
where I can't protect them.
我内心忍不住去想
And part of me can't help thinking that...
这是我活该
that I deserve this...
因为我认为自己可以拥有如此之多
for thinking that I could have so much.
但这种想法太贪婪
That anyone could.
我懂
I get it.
最近我也在深思这个问题
I've been thinking that a lot, too, lately.
我怎么做都不够
How I can never do enough.
我的错误盖过了我曾经做过的所有好事
How my mistakes outweigh all the good I've ever done.
但事情并非如此
But it's not true.
也不能如此
It can't be.
我们会救下他们
And we're going to save them.
露易丝  乔纳森和整个星球
Lois, Jonathan, this whole planet.
我们已经做过很多次  这次也能做到
We've done it a dozen times and we're going to do it again.
你现在怎么会如此希望满怀
How are you so... hopeful right now?
今天你和我一样失去了许多
You've lost just as much as I have today.
失去了阿尔戈  还有你妈妈
Argo, your mom...
在我们父母把我们送到地球来之前
Before our parents sent us to Earth...
这里的人根本不知道氪星
nobody here knew about Krypton.
现在有关于氪星的故事  庆典和博物馆展览
Now, there are stories, celebrations, museum exhibits.
就像你与家人分享了自己的家乡
Just like you shared our home with your family,
我们与这个世界一起分享了我们的家乡
we shared our home with this whole world.
氪星不只是一个地方  还象征着一种精神
Krypton's not just a place, it's a spirit.
希望与牺牲
It's hope. It's sacrifice.
那是我们父母为我们所做的
It's what our parents did for us.
那是你为乔纳森所做的
What you did for Jonathan.
我们为正义而战  这让我们父母感到自豪
We have made our parents proud by fighting for what's right.
所以我们必须继续战斗
So, we have to keep fighting.
只要那种精神还在
And as long as that spirit is alive,
氪星就会永存
Krypton will never die.
-你要见我吗  -是的
- You wanted to see me? - I did.
我有东西要给你
I have something for you.
是什么
What is it?
打开看看就知道了
Only one way to find out.
请告诉我你打算穿上这件战衣
Okay, please tell me you're planning on wearing this.
我觉得这件战衣不适合我
I don't think that that one would fit me.
至少要有一位绿箭侠
There should always be at least one Green Arrow.
老爸  我不行
Dad, I can't.
米娅  监视者让我失去了很多
You know, Mia, the Monitor has taken a lot from me.
但我会一直感激
But I will always be grateful for the time
他给了我能与你相处的时光
he has given me with you.
如果你不穿上这件战衣  没人有资格穿
If you're not gonna wear this, no one should.
是你努力得来的
You earned it.
穿上试试看吧  我要去找巴里
Just try it on, okay? I gotta find Barry.
现今世上速度最快的人
The fastest man alive shows up late to the Crisis
在我们期待已久的这场危机中迟迟未出现
we've been expecting for years.
这可有损颜面啊  巴里
It's not the... it's not the best look, Barry.
莱拉让我们去侦察量子塔
Lyla had us doing some recon of the quantum towers.
但是你记不记得报纸报道说
But listen, do you remember the newspaper article
我带你去看了时间穹顶
I showed you on the time vault?
红色天空和一场危机
Red skies and a "crisis"?
监视者证实了报纸上的报道并不属实
Okay, well, the Monitor confirmed the papers had lied and...
而且在这场危机中  我会死
in this Crisis, I'm supposed to die.
-不  -不
- No. - No?
我们要好好谈谈  就现在
We need to talk. Now!
你在和谁说话
Who're you talking to?
给我出来
Hey, right now!
我们已经没什么好谈的了  奥利弗
We are past the time for discussion, Oliver.
我和你达成过共识的
You and I had an agreement.
我死
I die.
让巴里和卡拉活下去
Barry and Kara live!
是的  为了保持宇宙平衡
Yes... to keep the cosmic balance.
你为什么要和巴里说他会死
So, why are you telling Barry that he's gonna die?
去年我放过你朋友一命
I spared your friends' lives
好让他们拯救他们的世界
so they could save their world last year.
但是这次威胁不同寻常
This... is a very different threat.
不要再戏耍我了
You need to stop playing games with me.
告诉我反监视者为什么要做这些事
You tell me why the Anti-Monitor is doing this.
然后告诉我怎么阻止他
And then tell me how I'm going to prevent it.
不知道你将要面对的是什么意味着
Not knowing what you're fighting means
你将会为所有可能做准备
you will prepare for every possibility.
因为这个威胁将会
Because this threat brings with it
终结所有现实中的
the annihilation of all life
所有生命
in all realities.
你现在能理解我们现在
Do you now comprehend the scope...
所面对威胁的重要程度了吗
of the danger we all now face?
你是趁着末日来逮捕我的吗
Are you here to arrest me during the apocalypse,
还是想来杀我
or to try and kill me
因为那天你没有成功
because you weren't successful the other day?
我不是想要伤害你  莉娜
I wasn't trying to hurt you, Lena.
我是想阻止你使用大清洗
I was trying to stop you from using Myriad.
是吗  这就是为什么你用克莱莫卫星瞄准我吗
Right. Is that why you had a Claymore satellite aimed at me?
我没有用大清洗  是伊芙·泰斯马克做的
And I didn't use Myriad, that was Eve Tessmacher.
你我都知道事实并非如此
You and I both know that that isn't true.
天空之所以变红
The reason the sky is red,
整个星球都感觉要散架了
and the planet feels like it's falling apart
是因为它确实要散了
is because it is.
有一股反物质能量
There is an anti-matter wave
正在撕裂整个宇宙
that is tearing through the universe right now,
它将会毁灭地球
and it will destroy Earth
如果卡拉和其他英雄没办法阻止它的话
if Kara and the other heroes don't stop it.
现在  我在和荣恩做一些保险
Now, I am working with J'onn to hedge our bets
准备进行撤离
and mount an evacuation,
但是要做到这些
but in order to do that...
我们需要你的帮助
we need your help.
真对不起我骗了你
Look, I am sorry that I lied to you.
不仅是我  不仅是卡拉
And not just me, and not just Kara...
是我们所有人
it was all of us.
荣恩和布莱尼  还有尼娅
J'onn and Brainy and Nia.
你知道吗  你真让我信了你恨超女
You know, you actually had me believe that you hated Supergirl.
那个不是我假装的
I wasn't pretending about that.
那个是...  说来话长
And that is a... long story.
听着  我知道你感觉被我们伤害了
Listen, I-- I know that you feel burned by us.
我现在不管说什么
And that there is nothing that I can say
都不可能改变这一切
in this moment that is going to change that.
但如果能请你把情感先放一旁
But if you could please just put your feelings aside,
荣恩和我真的  真的需要你的帮助
J'onn and I really, really, need your help.
我不需要你的道歉  艾丽克斯
I don't want your apology, Alex.
因为你再也不会拥有我的友谊和信任
'Cause you will never again have my friendship or my trust.
我从你们所有人身上学到了一课
I have learned my lesson from all of you.
但如果是世界有危险  我当然会帮忙
But if the world is at stake, then of course, I'll help.
真可笑  你居然以为我不会帮忙
It is hubris of you to think that I wouldn't,
但是  你已经表达的很清楚
but then, you've made it perfectly clear
这么些年来你有多轻视我  所以...
how little you've thought of me these last few years, so...
你需要我做些什么
what do you need me to do?
不管那里边是什么  它起作用了
Whatever is inside there, it's working
反物质能量停下了  并且正在逐渐消失
The anti-matter wave has stopped and it's slowly dissipating.
我们要怎么保护那东西不被我们一无所知
How do we protect that thing from an enemy we know nothing about,
却知道要来临敌人破坏掉
but we know is coming?
我们进去
We head inside...
找到有效的战术位置
stake out strategic positions.
如果我们布下防御  我们就能控制战斗
If we're fortified, we control the battle.
这个量级的地震可能毁掉整个海岸线
Earthquake that magnitude could overwhelm the entire coast.
去  帮助止损
Go. Help contain the damage.
走吧  这里交给我们
Go! We got this.
咱们进去吧
Let's go inside and dig in.
地球十六
星城  2046年
你一定是在逗我玩
You've gotta be kidding me.
我儿子的救生船降落在这里的几率有多大
What are the odds that my son's pod landed here?
三十八亿二千七百万分之一
Three billion, eight hundred and twenty seven million to one.
但是救生船没降落在这里
but the pod didn't land here.
但你说乔纳森就在这里
But you said that this is where Jonathan is.
是的  我追踪他到这里
Yes. This is where I tracked him.
但我不理解为什么奥利弗·奎恩会绑架婴儿
But I can't speculate as to why Oliver Queen would kidnap a baby.
他可能认为是在拯救他
Well, he probably thought he was rescuing him.
我是说  星城不是养孩子的地方
I mean, Star City is no place for a child.
等我找回乔纳森再谢他
Well, I'll thank him when I have Jonathan back.
与此同时  我们应该分开
In the meantime, we should split up--
这真是多余
This is unnecessary.
奥利弗
Oliver?
Oliver.
乔纳森
Jonathan!
是是  你去找乔纳森  我呆在这里
Yes. Yes, you go get Jonathan. I'll... I'll stay here,
什么  不
What? No.
不  这不可能
No, it's not possible.
你死了
You're dead.
你
You...
你和金牌号一起沉了
you went down with the Gambit.
但是我回来了  记得吗
But I came back. Remember?
我在炼狱岛上找到了你
I found you in Lian Yu.
我一定是发疯了
I must be losing my mind.
不  奥利  你没有
No, Ollie, you're not--
你没有  你...  这说来话长
You're not. You're... It's just a long story.
相当长
The longest.
谢谢你  奥利佛
Thank you, Oliver.
谢谢你帮助我的孩子
Thank you for helping my baby.
那么  这是什么
So, what is this?
暴风雨之前的宁静吗
The proverbial calm before the storm?
差不多吧
Something like that.
记住  米娅  不管发生什么...
Remember, Mia, whatever happens...
去找你的母亲
find your mother.
告诉她我有多爱她
Tell her how much I love her.
好吧
Okay.
当莱拉说一个军队
When Lyla said an army,
我以为她是指  军人
I thought she meant an... army.
她是这么说的  只不过
She did. It's just that...
我们从没有面对过这样的军队
we've never faced one like this before.
"一只军队"  他说"一只军队"  这更像是十个
"One army." She said, "One army." It's more like ten!
-非常好  -我有个好老师
- Very nice. - Learned from the best.
找掩护
Take cover!
他们想要侵入高塔
They're trying to breach the tower.
我们不能任由其发生
Well, we can't let that happen!
那个升级我现在要了
I'll take that upgrade now.
现在我不需要丢四肢就可以碰这个了吗
Oh, uh, if I can have one of those without losing an appendage.
太酷了
Oh, so cool!
超棒的平衡性  碳纤维
Incredibly balanced. Carbon fiber?
-你朋友话真多  -是  习惯就好
- Your friend talks a lot. - Yeah, you get used to it.
雷  集中注意力
Hey, Ray, focus!
正在集中
Focusing.
现在  只要让我们
Now, if we can just charge
给你的蝙蝠镖充上我压缩光能量
your Batarang with my compressed light energy.
来袭
Incoming!
不错啊
Not bad.
爸爸
Dad!
它们数量太多了
There's too many of them.
你需要帮助吗
You want some help?
无需慌张
There's no need for panic.
超女和超人正在努力拯救这个星球
Supergirl and Superman are working hard to save this planet.
很快  外星飞船会环游地球
Soon, alien ships will begin circling the globe,
搭载人们去安全地点
picking people up and taking you to safety.
艾丽克斯说服莉娜了吗
Did Alex get Lena on board?
是的  她们正在建造传送门
Yeah, they're working on the portal now.
我只希望荣恩能带来足够的飞船
I just hope J'onn can get enough ships.
这里可是有数十亿的人要离开这个星球
There are literally billions of people to get off the planet.
正因如此布莱尼才给了荣恩他的钥匙
That's why Brainy left J'onn his keys.
什么的钥匙
Keys to what?
末日军团留在这里的
The Legion left it here.
正是时候  荣恩
Right on time, J'onn.
你准备好进行撤离了吗
Are you ready to get this evacuation underway?
让人们围成一团  然后我开始传送
Start getting people into groups and I'll start beaming them up.
只希望艾丽克斯和莉娜能及时做出传送门
Let's just hope Alex and Lena get that portal on in time
这样我们能有地方去
so we have somewhere to go.
-这边请  -好了
- Go ahead. This way. - All right,
各位  咱们开始上船吧
people, let's get in to the ship.
量子塔镇压住了能量波
The quantum tower is keeping the wave at bay.
超女正在
Supergirl is...
非常努力的保护它
fighting really hard to protect it,
但我们得赶快让这传送门运转起来
but we've got to get this portal up and running.
我正在努力  但是物质传送门
I'm trying! But the transmatter portal
是通过合成多电子阴离子来实现的
works by synthesizing polyelectronic anions.
如果当我和缺口装置连接时
And if I don't get the energy levels right
我没有达到足够的能量水平
when I interface with the breach device,
当飞船穿过传送门时就会解体
then the ships will disintegrate when they fly right through it.
-好吧  这可不是个好选择 - 是的
- Right. That is not a good option. - No.
你有想过用逆变量
Have you thought about using an inverse variable
来计算微分吗
to help calculate the differential?
伽利恩理论
Galleon's theory.
好主意  一个逆β衰变
That's smart. An inverse beta-decay
计算组分夸克  这是可行的
to figure constituent quark, that could work.
谢了
Thanks.
不客气  只是
Yeah, um... just...
继续研究  有我在
keep working. I've got your back.
我从没想过会再见到你
I never thought I'd see you again.
星城
2046年
平行世界的一个好处
One of the benefits of parallel Earths.
平行世界
Parallel Earths?
似乎你的
It would appear that your
现实比我的要奇怪些
reality is a little... stranger than mine.
你是真的不知道
You really have no idea.
我这辈子
All my life...
我都想着
I just wanted to...
为把你带上船而道歉
to apologize for bringing you on that boat.
但这个你都不是那个你
But you aren't even you.
奥利
Ollie.
如果你口中的我就是我
If your me was anything like I was,
那登上金牌号就是她的选择
then getting on the Gambit with you was her choice.
在我的世界里  那次旅行
And in my world, that trip...
引发了一系列事件
it set off a whole series of events
那是你我做梦也想不到的
that neither you or I could've ever dreamed of.
你成了一个英雄
You became a hero,
为人夫  为人父
a husband, a father.
我穿梭在时光中感到前所未有的快乐
And I'm flying through time happier than I've ever been.
如果我没有跟你上船
And none of that would've ever happened
这些都不会发生
if I didn't get on that boat with you.
这就是命运
It was destiny.
抱歉打断在这个世界的历史上
I'm... sorry to break up what I'm sure must be
最奇怪的重逢
the strangest reunion in the history of the world,
但是  如果我们现在不走
but, um, if we don't leave now,
恐怕我们的外推器
I'm afraid our extrapolator
可能会没有足够能量送我们回家
might not have enough power for us to return home.
等等  什么是外推器
Wait, what's an extrapolator?
说来话长
It's another long story.
在每一个地球上
You're a good man...
你都是好人
on every Earth.
-就这样吗  -就这么简单吗
- Is that it? - Like that was easy?
他们在房顶上
They're on the roof.
外面发生了什么
What's happening out there?
天空又变红了  反物质波在移动
The skies are red again, the anti-matter wave's moving,
传送门还没打开
and the portal isn't open yet.
来了更多影魔
There's more shadow demons incoming.
卡拉  克拉克去房顶
Kara, Clark, get to the roof.
让塔重新运作
Get the tower operational again.
我们在后面挡住他们
We'll stay behind and hold them off.
那些是太阳能电池板吗
Are those solar panels?
看起来挺像的
Looks close enough.
我们肯定不可能给它供电
We won't be able to power it definitely.
我们只是争取点时间
We just need to buy more time.
我们可能会失去地球  但我们仍然可以拯救人类
We might lose the planet, but we can still save the people.
你快好了吗
You almost got it?
我觉得快完成了
Almost done, I think.
很好  系统准备好了
Yes! Systems are a go.
计算目的地  目的地设置完成
Calculating destination... destination set.
提出伽利恩理论这点很聪明
Smart call with Galleon's theory.
侥幸猜中  但你才是真的天才  所以
Oh, lucky guess. But you're the real genius here, so...
不要把我们一起工作误认为是友谊
Don't mistake us working together for friendship.
我之前跟你说过
I told you before,
卡拉和你说了你的身份  我接受了
Kara and you showed me who you were and I accept that.
现在  我们去帮人们登船吧
Now, let's go help people get on these ships.
你把自己逼得太紧了
That was too close for comfort.
总是要胜过我  是吧
Always gotta one-up me, huh?
-有用吗  -你成功了
- Did it work? - You did it.
塔重新运作了  传送门开启了
The tower is working again and the portal is open.
但船队要抓紧了
Uh, but the ships better be fast.
超充电没有阻止反物质波
The Supers' charge didn't actually stop the wave,
只是减慢了速度
it just slowed it down.
根据布莱尼的算法
According to Brainy's algorithm,
传送门能与地球相连十四分钟
we have 14 minutes before it makes contact with Earth.
那我们最好分秒必争
Well, then we better make every minute count.
我们来支援你们
We've got your back.
我们得阻止那些影魔靠近
We need to keep those shadow demons at bay
直到最后一艘船通过
until every last ship gets through--
好了  快上船
All right, get to the ships!
注意残骸  各位
Keep your eyes open for debris, people!
大家保持秩序  快走
Keep it orderly, people. Come on.
詹姆斯留给我的
James left it for me.
战斗失败了
The battle is lost!
我们必须撤退  为之后的战斗节约资源
We must retreat and save our resources for battles yet to come.
奥利弗  奥利
Oliver! Oli--
奥利弗  时间到了
Oliver! It is time!
地球疏散完了吗
Has the planet been evacuated yet?
还没有
Not entirely.
那时间就没到
Then it's not time.
地球一
星城
奥利弗
Oliver.
他战斗到生命的最后一刻
He fought to his last breath.
他明白每一刻都会拯救另一个生命
Knowing every moment was another life saved.
-拯救  -你的世界不复存在
- Saved? - Your universe is no more.
75.3亿人
Of 7.53 billion...
30亿人乘坐庞大的舰队
three billion souls made it to Earth-1
来到了地球一
on the armada of ships.
我估计有十亿人
I calculate one billion souls
因为他的崇高牺牲而幸存下来
survived due to his noble sacrifice.
纳什
Nash?
那是很久以前了  现在不是了
Once upon a time. Not anymore.
现在  我只是一个在赎罪的人
Now, I'm simply a man serving his penance.
赎什么罪
Penance for what?
我把反监视者从监禁中释放出来
I freed the Anti-Monitor from his confinement only...
只为了让他变成一个贱民
to become a... Pariah.
被判处只许观看不能插手
Sentenced to bear witness to his actions.
奥利弗
Oliver!
没事的  莎拉
It's okay, Sara.
这是我的命运
This is my destiny.
-奥利弗  -巴里
- Oliver. - Barry?
你  我的朋友
You, my friend...
是我们中最棒的
are the very best of us.
我因为你和卡拉
I gave it all up...
放弃了一切
for you and Kara.
你是什么意思
What-- What do you mean?
我需要你们两个
I need the two of you to...
成为
be the one to...
拯救我们的人
to save us now.
米娅
Mia...
爸爸
Dad.
别忘了去找你母亲
Don't forget to find your mother.
好的
Okay.
找到威廉
Find William.
告诉他我很爱他
Tell him how much I love him.
我爱你  米娅
I love you, Mia.
你把我记在心中  好吗
You keep me in your heart, okay?
-爸爸  -好吗
- Dad... - Okay?
不应该是这样的
It was not supposed to be like this.
这不是我预见的结局
This is not his ending I foresaw.
事情的结果和我预料的不一样
Things are turning out differently than I expected.
但有一件事是肯定的
But one thing is certain.
我们知道的一切
Everything we know...
现在的一切
everything there is...
过去的一切
and everything there ever was...
都将毁灭
is doomed.